Finding Aid for Margaret Keal Knowles photograph collection, ca. 1860-ca. 1920
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Margaret Keal Knowles photograph collection ca. 1860-ca. 1920
Knowles, Margaret Keal, collector.
0.25 linear feet
92381 UA 2
Family photographs accumulated by Margaret Keal Knowles.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was accumulated by Margaret Keal Knowles (donor no. 5889 ).
No further additions to the collection are expected.
The collection is open to research.
No biographical information available.
The collection consists of portraits and other photographs of Washington Irving Keal, Nellie Annetta Keal, Thomas Keal, Lucy Ann Wyman Smith, and other members of the Keal, Crandell, Smith, and White families of Ann Arbor and Dexter, Michigan. Apart from portraits, the collection also includes photographs of buildings in Dexter, Michigan, the store of John L. Crandell in Rochester, Michigan, and the Orin White house in Ann Arbor.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Dwellings.; Business enterprises--Michigan--Rochester.; Crandell, John L.; Crandall family.; Dexter (Mich.); Dwellings--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Keal, Nellie Annetta.; Keal, Thomas.; Keal, Washington Irving, 1842-; Keal family.; Rochester (Mich.)--Business enterprises.; Smith, Lucy Ann.; Smith family.; White, Orin, 1794-1864.; White family.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Photographs
  - Crandell family (family of donor's mother) (Box 1)
    - Alice Crandell (Box 1)
    - John Lincoln Crandell (1860-1945), 2 photos (Box 1)
    - John Lincoln Crandell in his store, Rochester, Mich. (Box 1)
    - Ralph Sperry (b. 1876) (Box 1)
    - Inez Sperry Stevens (Box 1)
    - Julia Twitchell Van Etta (1848-1911), 2 photos (Box 1)
    - Neva Sperry Crandell's 1st grade class, Whitehall, Mich., 1900 and 1904-1905, 2 photos (Box 1)
  - Dexter, Mich. and University of Michigan, 7 photos (Box 1)
  - Keal ancestors
    - Thomas Keal (1814-1853) (Box 1)
    - Rosalind Ela Keal (1811-1867) (Box 1)
  - Keal family
    - Keal Family group (Box 1)
      ( includes Washington Irving Keal (1842-1907), Jennie Smith Keal (1845-1916), George Irving Keal (b. 1876), Harry Morton Keal (b. 1880, father of donor), and Nellie Annetta Keal (1871-1910))
    - George Irving Keal (b. 1876) (Box 1)
    - Jennie E. Keal (Box 1)
    - Washington Irving Keal (1842-1907), 8 photos (Box 1)
  - Other family members
    - Nellie Annetta Keal (Mrs. George S. Francisco; 1871-1910), 5 photos (Box 1)
    - Nellie with her mother, Jennie E. Smith Keal (b. 1845-1916, grandmother of donor) (Box 1)
    - Nellie with brothers Harry Morton and George Irving (Box 1)
  - Smith and White families
    - Lucy Ann Wyman Smith (d.1847) (Box 1)
    - Family group (Box 1)
      (Seated: Louis Clark (d.1930s), Carrie Smith Clark (Mrs. Will) Will Clark; Standing: Charles Clark; on wall are portraits of Louisa Merian and Oliver M. Smith, Jr. (b. 1815)
    - Ione Keal White (b. 1840) and husband Orpheus White of Hartford, Mich. (Box 1)
    - Residence of Orrin White, Ann Arbor (Box 1)
      (built in 1837 of cobblestones)